export const GEOGRAPHYA2010 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The distance by road from AKPABIA junction to the bridge on a tributary of River Dupe in the eastern part of the map is approximately",
A: "4.50 km",
B: "4.80 km",
C: "5.80 km",
D: "6.80 km",
answer: "B. 4.80 km",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The scale of the map expressed as Representative Fraction is",
A: "1:50,000",
B: "1:100,000",
C: "1:150,000",
D: "1:250,000",
answer: "A. 1:50,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The bearing of Agidi from Toje is",
A: "180°",
B: "200°",
C: "270°",
D: "300°",
answer: "D. 300°",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The feature marked Q is a",
A: "Valley",
B: "Col",
C: "Spur",
D: "Gentle slope",
answer: "C. Spur",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The feature marked G is known as",
A: "Intermont plateau",
B: "Wind gap",
C: "Valley",
D: "Col",
answer: "D. Col",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Y is an example of a",
A: "Scarp slope",
B: "Yardang",
C: "Dip slope",
D: "Gorge",
answer: "A. Scarp slope",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The occupations of the people of in Toje are likely to be",
A: "Lumbering and fishing",
B: "Fishing and farming",
C: "Farming and lumbering",
D: "Fishing and mining",
answer: "C. Farming and lumbering",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following settlement is most suitable for the location of a Sawmill?",
A: "AKPABIA",
B: "Fume",
C: "Toil",
D: "Toje",
answer: "D. Toje",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The relief feature marked S is called a",
A: "Ridge",
B: "Plateau",
C: "Col",
D: "Knoll",
answer: "D. Knoll",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The south eastern section of River Kayera has all the following except a",
A: "Flood plain",
B: "Meander belt",
C: "Tributary",
D: "Narrow valley",
answer: "D. Narrow valley",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Uranus is unique among the planets in the solar system because it",
A: "Is larger than all the planets",
B: "Has no satellite",
C: "Revolves in a clockwise direction",
D: "Has circular light and dark bands around it",
answer: "C. Revolves in clockwise direction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. If someone in a town A (20°B) telephones a friend in another town B (16°W) at 10:00 am, at what local time will his friend receive the call?",
A: "7:36am",
B: "9:36 am",
C: "12:24 pm",
D: "12:36 pm",
answer: "A. 7:36 am",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The chemical composition of the core of the earth is",
A: "Silica and magnesia",
B: "Silica and copper",
C: "Iron and nickel.",
D: "Iron and mica",
answer: "C. Iron and nickel.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The outermost layer of the earth is the",
A: "Mantle",
B: "Core",
C: "Lithosphere",
D: "Lithosphere",
answer: "C. Lithosphere",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Intrusive igneous rocks refer to rocks that are formed",
A: "By sedimentation",
B: "At some depth in the earth’s crust by cooling of magma;",
C: "By deposition of sediments under water.",
D: "On the earth’s surface.",
answer: "B. At some depth in the earth’s crust by cooling of magma",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Rocks formed from the remains of dead organisms are called",
A: "Granitic rocks.",
B: "Calcareous rocks.",
C: "Plutonic rocks.",
D: "Basaltic rocks.",
answer: "B. Calcareous rocks.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. An example of chemically sedimentary rock is",
A: "Conglomerate",
B: "Rock salt.",
C: "Coal.",
D: "Clay.",
answer: "B. Rock salt.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. If the temperature at the foot of a mountain 3000 in high is 27° C, the temperature at the summit of the mountain will be",
A: "20.5°C",
B: "14.0°C",
C: "7.5° C",
D: "0.5°C",
answer: "C. 7.5° C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A volcano that has not erupted for a long time period but shows signs of possible eruption is said to be",
A: "Active",
B: "Dormant",
C: "Extinct",
D: "Dead.",
answer: "B. Dormant",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Tectonic lakes are formed from",
A: "Wind abrasion.",
B: "Rock flow.",
C: "Deposition.",
D: "Earth movement.",
answer: "D. Earth movement.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A stalactite can best be described as",
A: "A long slender pillar of calcium deposit that hangs from the roof of a cave.",
B: "A long slender pillar of calcium deposit that grows from the floor of a cave.",
C: "A short, fat limestone pillar that grows from the floor of a limestone cave.",
D: "A steep pillar of rock rising from sea which was formally part of the land.",
answer: "A. A long slender pillar of calcium deposit that hangs from the roof of a cave.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following features is formed by marine erosion?",
A: "Bar",
B: "Hanging valley.",
C: "Stack",
D: "Dry valley,",
answer: "C. Stack",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following features is found along the lower course of a river?",
A: "Gorges.",
B: "Rapids.",
C: "Terraces.",
D: "Meanders.",
answer: "D. Meanders.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is not a feature along a rocky coast?",
A: "Tombolo",
B: "Cave",
C: "Stack",
D: "Geo",
answer: "A. Tombolo",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The seaward portion of the headland which remains as a pillar after the collapse of an arch resulting from wave erosion is known as",
A: "Gloup",
B: "Spit",
C: "Dyke",
D: "Stack",
answer: "D. Stack",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The landform shown in the diagram below is",
A: "An inselberg.",
B: "Rock pedestal",
C: "A barchans.",
D: "A yardang.",
answer: "B. Rock pedestal",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Deflation is most effective in dry areas because",
A: "Mechanical weathering of rocks is strongest in dry areas.",
B: "The work of wind is greatly aided by the action of running water in dry areas.",
C: "The cloudless skies in dry areas effectively encourage wind erosion",
D: "The soil is bare and loose in dry areas.",
answer: "D. The soil is bare and loose in dry areas.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Continental shelves are important to man because they provide good",
A: "Deltas.",
B: "Tourist centres.",
C: "Ports.",
D: "Fishing grounds",
answer: "D. Fishing grounds",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. All the following favour the formation of a delta except",
A: "Weak currents and tidal waves at the mouth.",
B: "A large load carried by the river.",
C: "A lake in the middle course of the river.",
D: "A long, gentle lower course.",
answer: "C. A lake in the middle course of the river.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of these bring cool conditions during the day to coastal areas?",
A: "Land breeze",
B: "Northeast trades",
C: "Monsoon winds",
D: "Sea breeze",
answer: "D. Sea breeze",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The movement of ocean waters is influenced by",
A: "Rainfall and winds.",
B: "Density and winds",
C: "Temperature and Winds",
D: "Humidity and winds.",
answer: "C. Temperature and Winds",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A coastline of drowned river valley is",
A: "Fiord coastline",
B: "Ria coastline",
C: "Raised coastline",
D: "Neutral coastline.",
answer: "B. Ria coastline",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Frontal rainfall is caused by",
A: "Extreme heat radiated from the earth’s surface.",
B: "The meeting of dry and cold air masses.",
C: "Wind blowing towards a mountain.",
D: "The meeting of warm and cold air masses.",
answer: "D. The meeting of warm and cold air masses.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The suffix added to the name of a cloud to signify rainfall is",
A: "Cumulus",
B: "Nimbus.",
C: "Cirrus.",
D: "Stratus.",
answer: "A. Cumulus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. It is characterized by high uniform temperatures and heavy well distributed rainfall throughout the year with no distinct dry seasons. This brief description refers to",
A: "Tundra climate",
B: "Equatorial climate",
C: "Temperate continental climate",
D: "Hot desert climate.",
answer: "B. Equatorial climate",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Many towns in the coastal regions of West Africa are densely populated because",
A: "Coastal areas experience more extreme climate.",
B: "People prefer plains to highland.",
C: "Existence of adequate supply of salt water.",
D: "Industries are concentrated in the coastal areas.",
answer: "D. Industries are concentrated in the coastal areas.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following settlement types is the largest?",
A: "City",
B: "Metropolis",
C: "Megalopolis",
D: "Town",
answer: "C. Megalopolis",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The zone where cold and warm currents meet may be dangerous to ships because",
A: "The rains are torrential.",
B: "It is a zone of thunderstorm",
C: "The fog that forms reduces visibility.",
D: "Harmattan winds are formed.",
answer: "C. The fog that forms reduces visibility.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following is a major advantage of roads over rails?",
A: "Roads links industrial towns.",
B: "Roads join one settlement to another.",
C: "Roads could be built almost anywhere.",
D: "Roads are used to carry heavy goods.",
answer: "C. Roads could be built almost anywhere.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following minerals is important in the generation of geothermal power?",
A: "Copper",
B: "Gas",
C: "Uranium",
D: "Phosphates",
answer: "A. Copper",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Biogas is produced from",
A: "Animal and human waste",
B: "Industrial waste",
C: "Solar radiation",
D: "Sea water",
answer: "A. Animal and human waste",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following factors does not influence the location of manufacturing industries?",
A: "Raw materials",
B: "Quarrying site",
C: "Transport",
D: "Market",
answer: "B. Quarrying site",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following methods is not employed in the mining of gold?",
A: "Drilling",
B: "Shaft",
C: "Open cast",
D: "Adit",
answer: "A. Drilling",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following does not share boundary with West Africa?",
A: "Cameroon",
B: "Central Africa",
C: "Gulf of guinea",
D: "Sahara desert",
answer: "B. Central Africa",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following areas has a low population density in West Africa?",
A: "Western Senegal",
B: "Central Mali",
C: "Western Nigeria",
D: "Southern Ghana",
answer: "B. Central Mali",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Hot desert regions have a great potential for",
A: "Thermal energy",
B: "Solar energy",
C: "Hydroelectric power",
D: "Nuclear energy",
answer: "B. Solar energy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The major crop grown in the Nile valley is",
A: "BarIey",
B: "Cotton",
C: "Guinea corn",
D: "Maize",
answer: "B. Cotton",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. When the West Africa gas pipeline takes of natural gas will be sent to Ghana from",
A: "Nigeria",
B: "Liberia",
C: "Togo",
D: "Benin",
answer: "A. Nigeria",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. All the following countries in West Africa have important fishing industries except",
A: "Senegal",
B: "Ghana",
C: "Nigeria",
D: "Burkina Faso",
answer: "D. Burkina Faso",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following does not limit the use of river transport in Africa?",
A: "Waterfalls",
B: "High volume of water",
C: "Floating vegetation",
D: "Seasonality of river",
answer: "B. High volume of water",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]